Lluis Artus | Dr.

Harald Løvenskiolds vei 4 – 0760 Oslo – Norway

Born: 16th of December, 1992

☑ Ilartuss7@gmail.comin Iluis-artus-suarez※ Ilartuss7¶ GitHub¶ V0c1H8IAAAAJ

https://lluisartussuarez.github.io/



Personal Statement

PhD in computational chemistry, specializing in the simulation of catalytic systems. I have been studying CO_2 hydrogenation mechanisms for seven years and enantioselective hydrogenation of olefins for two years. Using density functional theory, classical molecular dynamics, and microkinetic modeling, I can study the role of catalysts in the reactions. That information is essential to identify favorable and detrimental factors that determine the reaction rates and allow the development of faster and more stable catalysts.

Machine learning applied to theoretical chemistry is rising in popularity. Therefore, last year, I started training myself in it. I have been reading about state-of-the-art ML techniques, attending an ML conference applied to computational chemistry, and, in November 2023, enrolling in IBM's online course on Machine Learning. There, I learned about exploratory data analysis, regression, classification, and unsupervised models, but it will also cover genetic models and deep learning. I look forward to implementing what I learned into a practical application.

Professional experience

Science	
KTH Royal Institute of Technology	Stockholm, Sweden
Postdoctoral researcher	2022-2024
Project: "Forcefields for electrochemistry in metal-organic frameworks"	
Project: "Reaction mechanisms of enantioselective hydrogenation of olefines"	
Nordic Consortium for CO ₂ Conversion	Scandinavia
Postdoctoral researcher	2022-2024
Project: "Modelling of CO2 electroreduction in metal-organic frameworks"	
PhD student	2018-2021
Project: "Rational catalyst design for the hydrogenation of CO ₂ derivates"	
Lecturer in	
Workshop in Microkinetic Modeling with COPASI	2022
Stockholm, Sweden. April 28-29	
Workshop in Microkinetic Modeling with COPASI	2019
Tromsø, Norway. March 26-27	
Internships	
Iceland University, Iceland	2022
Group of Egill Skúlason. Ab-initio molecular dynamics. November	

Valladolid University, Spain

2018

Group of Martin Jaraiz. Microkinetic modelling. June – July

ICIQ, Spain 2015-2016

Group of Feliu Maseras. Modelling of single electron transfers.

GMMF, Spain (Not paid)

2014-2015

Group of E. Carolina Sañudo. Synthesis and characterization of magnetic and fluorescent molecules.

Others.....

Frenchie Bistro Oslo, Norway

Waiter Sept. 2021 – Feb. 2022

Skogstad Hotel ***

Hemsedal, Norway

Waiter and housekeeper Summer. 2021 **Hotel Port-Bó*****Palafrugell, Spain

Receptionist Summers 2013 – 2015

Hotel & Spa Mas de Torrent *****

Torrent, Spain

Receptionist Summers 2009 – 2010



Academic education

Oslo University Oslo, Norway

Ph.D. Chemistry 2016-2021

Thesis: "Computational study on the deaminative hydrogenation of amides catalyzed by base metal complexes"

Rovira i Virgili University

Tarragona, Spain

M.Sc. Chemistry 2015-2016

Thesis: "Computational characterization of the mechanism of the reaction between Fe(I) complexes and aryl halides"

Barcelona University Barcelona, Spain

B.Sc. Chemistry 2010-2015

Thesis: "Synthesis and characterization of coordination compounds with a fluorescent ligand"

Courses and Certifications

Deep Learning and Reinforcement Learning 2024

Online. IBM course of >31h. October

Unsupervised Machine Learning 2024

Online. IBM course of >23h. June

Supervised Machine Learning: Classification 2024

Online. IBM course of >24h. April

Singularity workshop 2024

Stockholm, Sweden. February 12

Supervised Machine Learning: Regression 2024

Online. IBM course of >20h. February

Exploratory Data Analysis for Machine Learning 2023

Online. IBM course of >14h. December

Introduction to GPUs course	2023
Stockholm, Sweden. October 12-13	
Alpha fold v2.0 and RoseTTAFold Workshop Online. Aug. 31-Sep. 1	2021
8 th MOLCAS Users' Workshop Uppsala, Sweden, Nov. 20-24	2017



Computational chemistry

Reaction mechanism exploration

Software: Gaussian, Jaguar (Schrodinger), COPASI, Acuchem

Rational catalyst design of organometallic catalysts.

Microkinetic modelling for the design and interpretation of experimental kinetic experiments and for the evaluation of theoretical models.

Drug discovery and material science

Software: Amber, Gromacs, CP2K

Forcefield parametrization of organometallic systems

Free energy calculations: FEP, EVB, umbrella sampling, metadynamics Properties calculations: binding energies, diffusion coefficients, viscosities...

Cheminformatics

Software: RDKit, OpenBabel, molSimplify

Automatic interpretation of chemical databases

Automatic generation of molecular structures for future processing (e.g. machine learning)

Others

Software: NBO6, NCIPLOT, OpenMolcas, Chemcraft, PHI, ioChem-BD

Experimental chemistry.....

Basic training in

Good laboratory practices, NMR, MS, UV-Vis, FT-IR, Spectrofluorometry, HPLC, GC and SQUID.

Informatics.....

I have worked with supercomputers and computer clusters for eight years, at a user level.

I am comfortable with python, and have basic knowledge of C++, Fortran, bash, awk and seq.

The python libraries I use most are os, sys, shutil, pandas, numpy, scipy, matplotlib, seaborn, sklearn, rdkit, molSimplify and OpenBabel.

Most of my programming has been scripting for workflow automation or data analysis.

I recently started studying IBM's online courses on Machine Learning. I have completed "Exploratory Data Analysis", "Supervised Machine Learning, Regression and Classification", "Unsupervised Machine Learning" and "Deep Learning and Reinforcement Learning"



Seven articles published in scientific journals. H index of five. Cited more than a hundred times. Five first-authorships.